Assume everyone will betray you, and you'll never be disappointed.
Solo: A Star Wars Story is a science fiction,
adventure, action film directed by Ron Howard.
Through a series of daring escapades deep within a dark and dangerous criminal underworld, Han Solo meets
his mighty future copilot Chewbacca and encounters the notorious gambler Lando Calrissian.
Han Solo, played by Alden Ehrenreich.
Chewbacca, played by Joonas Suotamo.
Tobias Beckett, played by Woody Harrelson.
Qi'ra, played by Emilia Clarke.
Lando Calrissian, played by Donald Glover.
Val, played by Thandiwe Newton.
Solo: A Star Wars Story is a 2018 American space Western film directed by
Ron Howard and written by Jonathan and Lawrence Kasdan.
Produced by Lucasfilm Ltd., and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures, it
is the second Star Wars anthology film, following Rogue One (2016).
The film stars Alden Ehrenreich as Han Solo, with Woody Harrelson, Emilia Clarke, Donald Glover,
Thandiwe Newton, Phoebe Waller-Bridge, Joonas Suotamo, and Paul Bettany in supporting roles.
The film tells the origin story of Han Solo and Chewbacca, who join a heist within the criminal
underworld ten years prior to the events of the first Star Wars film (1977).
George Lucas began developing a Han Solo prequel in 2012 and
commissioned Lawrence Kasdan to write the screenplay.
After Lucas sold Lucasfilm to The Walt Disney Company in 2012, Kasdan was hired to write The
Force Awakens (2015), leaving his son Jonathan to complete the Solo script.
Principal photography began in January 2017 at Pinewood Studios,
with directors Phil Lord and Christopher Miller.
Both were fired in June 2017 following creative differences with
Lucasfilm, and Howard was hired as their replacement.
Solo is one of the most expensive films ever made,
with a budget of at least $275 million.
Solo premiered in Los Angeles on May 10, 2018, and was
released in North America on May 25.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics, which praised the cast (particularly Ehrenreich and
Glover), visuals, score, and action sequences, while some criticized the storyline and screenplay.
It was the first Star Wars film to be a box-office
bomb, grossing $393 million worldwide.
It received a nomination for Best Visual Effects at the 91st Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of spacecraft, smuggling
(contraband), prequel, spin off, space opera.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking.